[
    {
        "question": "RDS Reserved instances are available for multi-AZ deployments.",
        "choice1": "True",
        "choice2": "False",
        "choice3": "Filler",
        "choice4": "Filler",
        "answer": 1,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "If you are using Amazon RDS Provisioned IOPS storage with a Microsoft SQL Server database engine, what is the maximum size RDS volume you can have by default?",
        "choice1": "32TB",
        "choice2": "6TB",
        "choice3": "16TB",
        "choice4": "1TB",
        "choice5": "500GB",
        "answer": 3,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following data formats does Amazon Athena support?",
        "choice1": "Apache Parquet",
        "choice2": "Apache ORC",
        "choice3": "XML",
        "choice4": "JSON",
        "answer": "1,2,4",
        "multi": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "In RDS, what is the maximum value I can set for my backup retention period?",
        "choice1": "15 Days",
        "choice2": "30 Days",
        "choice3": "35 Days",
        "choice4": "45 Days",
        "answer": 3,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "DB security groups are used with DB instances that are not in a VPC and on the EC2-Classic platform. When you create a DB security group, you need to specify a destination port number.",
        "choice1":"False",
        "choice2":"True",
        "choice3":"Filler",
        "choice4":"Filler",
        "answer": 1,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is most suitable for OLAP?",
        "choice1": "ElastiCache",
        "choice2": "RDS",
        "choice3": "DynamoDB",
        "choice4": "Redshift",
        "answer": 4,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "In RDS, when are changes to the backup window implemented?",
        "choice1": "You cannot back up in RDS.",
        "choice2": "After 30 minutes",
        "choice3": "During the next scheduled maintenance window or immediately",
        "choice4": "The next day",
        "answer": 3,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "You are hosting a MySQL database on the root volume of an EC2 instance. The database is using a large number of IOPS, and you need to increase the number of IOPS available to it. What should you do?",
        "choice1": "Use CloudFront to cache the database.",
        "choice2": "Add 2 additional EBS SSD volumes and create a RAID 0 volume to host the database.",
        "choice3": "Migrate the database to an S3 bucket.",
        "choice4": "Migrate the database to Glacier.",
        "answer": 2,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "What data transfer charge is incurred when replicating data between Availability Zones for your Amazon RDS MySQL in a Multi-AZ deployment?",
        "choice1": "There is no charge associated with this action.",
        "choice2": "The charge is half of the standard data transfer charge.",
        "choice3": "The charge is the same as the standard data transfer charge.",
        "choice4": "The charge is double the standard data transfer charge.",
        "answer": 1,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a feature supported by DynamoDB?",
        "choice1": "Data reads that are either eventually consistent or strongly consistent",
        "choice2": "The ability to perform operations by using a user-defined primary key",
        "choice3": "The primary key can be either a single-attribute or a composite partition-sort key",
        "choice4": "Amazon DynamoDB supports MongoDB workloads.",
        "answer": 4,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "AWS's NoSQL product offering is known as ____.",
        "choice1": "DynamoDB",
        "choice2": "RDS",
        "choice3": "MongoDB",
        "choice4": "MySQL",
        "answer": 1,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "What happens to the I/O operations of a single-AZ RDS instance during a database snapshot or backup?",
        "choice1": "I/O operations will function normally.",
        "choice2": "I/O operations to the database are sent to a Secondary instance of a Multi-AZ installation (for the duration of the snapshot.)",
        "choice3": "I/O may be briefly suspended while the backup process initializes (typically under a few seconds), and you may experience a brief period of elevated latency.",
        "choice4": "Nothing.",
        "answer": 3,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "If I wanted to run a database on an EC2 instance, which of the following storage options would Amazon recommend?",
        "choice1": "S3",
        "choice2": "RDS",
        "choice3": "Glacier",
        "choice4": "EBS",
        "answer": 4,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "With new RDS DB instances, automated backups are enabled by default?",
        "choice1": "True",
        "choice2": "False",
        "choice3": "Filler",
        "choice4": "Filler",
        "answer": 1,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "You can SSH into and control the operating system where your Amazon RDS MySQL instance is running.",
        "choice1": "True",
        "choice2": "False",
        "choice3": "Filler",
        "choice4": "Filler",
        "answer": 2,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Which AWS service is ideal for Business Intelligence Tools/Data Warehousing?",
        "choice1": "Elastic Beanstalk",
        "choice2": "ElastiCache",
        "choice3": "DynamoDB",
        "choice4": "Redshift",
        "answer": 4,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Amazon's ElastiCache uses which two engines?",
        "choice1": "Redis & Memory",
        "choice2": "MyISAM & InnoDB",
        "choice3": "Reddit & Memcrush",
        "choice4": "Redis & Memcached",
        "answer": 4,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "How many copies of my data does RDS - Aurora store by default?",
        "choice1": "2",
        "choice2": "3",
        "choice3": "1",
        "choice4": "6",
        "answer": 4,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "MySQL installations default to port number ____.",
        "choice1": "1433",
        "choice2": "3389",
        "choice3": "3306",
        "choice4": "80",
        "answer": 3,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "If you want your application to check RDS for an error, have it look for an __ node in the response from the Amazon RDS API.",
        "choice1": "Exit",
        "choice2": "Error",
        "choice3": "Incorrect",
        "choice4": "Abort",
        "answer": 2,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "When creating an RDS instance, you can select the Availability Zone into which you deploy it.",
        "choice1": "False",
        "choice2": "True",
        "choice3": "Filler",
        "choice4": "Filler",
        "answer": 2,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Which AWS DB platform is most suitable for OLTP workloads?",
        "choice1":"Redshift",
        "choice2":"ElastiCache",
        "choice3":"DynamoDB",
        "choice4":"RDS",
        "answer": 4,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Under what circumstances would I choose provisioned IOPS over standard storage when creating an RDS instance?",
        "choice1": "If you use online transaction processing in your production environment.",
        "choice2": "If you have workloads that are not sensitive to latency/lag.",
        "choice3": "If this was a test Database.",
        "choice4": "If your business was trying to save money.",
        "answer": 1,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Which set of RDS database engines is currently available?",
        "choice1": "Aurora, MySQL, SQL Server, Cassandra",
        "choice2": "Amazon Aurora, MySQL, MariaDB, Oracle, SQL Server, and PostgreSQL",
        "choice3": "MariaDB, SQL Server, MySQL, Cassandra",
        "choice4": "PostgreSQL, MariaDB, MongoDB, Aurora",
        "answer": 2,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following DynamoDB features are chargeable, when using a single region?",
        "choice1": "Local secondary indexes",
        "choice2": "Incoming Data Transfer",
        "choice3": "Storage of Data",
        "choice4": "Read and Write Capacity",
        "answer": "3,4",
        "multi": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following AWS services is a non-relational database?",
        "choice1": "Amazon ElastiCache",
        "choice2": "Amazon DynamoDB",
        "choice3": "Amazon Redshift",
        "choice4": "Amazon RDS",
        "answer": 2,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Which database helps you store data in a relational format, with SQL language compatibility and capability of processing transactions?",
        "choice1": "RedShift",
        "choice2": "RDS",
        "choice3": "DynamoDB",
        "choice4": "ElastiCache",
        "answer": 2,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Which database do you suggest to have caching capability with a Redis compatible API?",
        "choice1": "RBD",
        "choice2": "DynamoDB",
        "choice3": "ElasticSearch",
        "choice4": "ElastiCache",
        "answer": 4,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "You are looking to perform OLTP, and would like to have the underlying storage with the maximum amount of replication and auto-scaling capability. What do you recommend?",
        "choice1": "ElastiCache",
        "choice2": "Redshift",
        "choice3": "Athena",
        "choice4": "RDS",
        "answer": 3,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "As a solution architect, you plan on creating a social media website where users can be friends with each other, and like each other's posts. You plan on performing some complicated queries such as 'What are the number of likes on the posts that have been posted by the friends of Mike?'. What database do you suggest?",
        "choice1": "RDS",
        "choice2": "Redshift",
        "choice3": "Neptune",
        "choice4": "ElasticSearch",
        "answer": 3,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "You would like to store big objects of 100 MB into a reliable and durable Key Value store. What do you recommend?",
        "choice1": "Athena",
        "choice2": "S3",
        "choice3": "DynamoDB",
        "choice4": "ElastiCache",
        "answer": 2,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "You would like to have a database which is efficient at performing analytical queries on large sets of columnar data. You would like to connect that Data Warehouse to a reporting and dashboard tool such as Amazon Quicksight. Which technology do you recommend?",
        "choice1": "RDS",
        "choice2": "S3",
        "choice3": "Redshift",
        "choice4": "Neptune",
        "answer": 3,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Your log data is currently stored in S3 and you would like to perform a quick analysis if possible serverless to filter the logs and find a user which may have completed an unauthorized action. Which technology do you recommend?",
        "choice1": "DynamoDB",
        "choice2": "Redshift",
        "choice3": "Athena",
        "choice4": "Glacier",
        "answer": 3,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Your gaming website is currently running on top of DynamoDB. Users have been asking for a search feature to find other gamers by name, with partial matches if possible. Which technology do you recommend to implement that feature?",
        "choice1": "DynamoDB",
        "choice2": "ElastiSearch",
        "choice3": "Neptune",
        "choice4": "Redshift",
        "answer": 2,
        "multi": 0
    }
]